OKENYI UCHECHUKWU RAPHAEL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Email me: rafaelokenyi@gmail.com Address: Billings way, Ikeja, Lagos, 100001.

Call me: +2347082201180

I'm a seasoned Software Developer specializing in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the MERN stack technologies encompassing MongoDB, Express, React and Node Js.

I possess a strong understanding of software engineering principles and a commitment to delivering highquality work. Adept at debugging software applications and working collaboratively with a team.

KEY SKILLS

- ♦ HTML 5
- **♦ CSS 3**
- ♦ JavaScript
- MongoDB
- Express Js
- React Js
- ♦ Node Js
- ♦ Bootstrap CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hemam Synergy - React Developer (Contract-based): July 2023 - September 2023

- Contracted to develop and maintain responsive web application using React Js for Hemam Synergy, ensuring optimal user experiences across various devices and screen sizes.
- Worked with a functional team to gather and define project requirements.
- Conducted code reviews and contributed to the improvement of coding standards and best practices within the development team.
- Developed user interface utilizing React is and Tailwind.

• Optimized the web application performance by identifying and addressing rendering issues, resulting in a significant improvement in loading time.

ICDAT Academia - Software Developer Intern: Nov 2022 - May 2023

- Collaborated with other developers to ensure code quality and functionality
- Deployed web application on various cloud platforms such as AWS.
- Developed, tested and deployed several web applications using React.
- Developed user interface utilizing React and CSS3.
- Monitored system performance, identified and resolved software issues.
- Collaborated with other developers on the design of features for applications
- Constructed API calls from the frontend code to communicate with backend services.

RKCC – Web Developer, (Contract-based): Feb 2021 – Jan 2022

- Leveraged mastery of HTML, CSS and JavaScript to build quality code for the firm.
- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure mobile compatibility of their website.
- Created clean, well-documented custom code and updates.

BilingoPlus Limited, Ukraine - Frontend Developer and Translator: July 2020 - Sep 2022

- Worked closely with UI UX designers and fellow frontend developers to build and maintain the company's website.
- Developed reusable code to enhance the website performance and efficiency, resulting in faster loading times and improved user experience.
- Successfully worked remotely for the entire two-year contract period, ensuring seamless communication and teamwork.
- Utilized Bilingual skills to serve as a contracted translator for the company during periods of high translation demand.
- Delivered high quality translation services, contributing to efficient completion of language related projects.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Nnamdi Azikiwe University | BSc in Computer Science | Awka, Anambra state | Nov 2019 – current
Internship at ICDAT Academia | Ikeja, Lagos state | Nov 2022 – July 2023

LANGUAGES

• English – fluent

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Soft skills

- Effective time management.
- Problem solving.
- Creativity.
- Teamwork.
- Excellent communication.